注意 近日移除
塞西利亚是第一个
Cecilia was the first to go.
你怎么弄成这样?  宝贝
What are you doing here?  Honey
你还小未经世事
You're not old enough to know how bad life gets.
显然 医生
Obviously, doctor
你从未当过13岁的女孩
you've never been a 13 year old girl.
处女之死
每个人都记得我们的邻居
Everyone dates the demise of our neighborhood
里斯本女孩们自杀的日子
from the suicides of the Lisbon girls.
人们在无精打采的榆树
People saw their clairvoyants in the wiped out elms
密歇根州 25年前
和日渐衰落的汽车工业中瞥见她们犀利的眼神
and the continuing decline of our auto industry.
年少的我们试着把碎片拼贴完整
Even then we tried putting the pieces together.
仍是失败了
We still can't.
现在每当我们在商务餐会或鸡尾派对上相遇
now whenever we meet at business lunches or cocktail parties
都会不由得在角落里重温那些证据
we find ourselves going over the evidence one more time.
只为了解那五个女孩
All to understand those five girls,
经过这么多年 她们仍铭刻在我们的脑海
who, after all these years, we can't get out of our minds.
塞西利亚 最小的一个 13岁
Cecilia, the youngest, was 13.
勒克斯 14岁
And Lux was 14.
邦妮 15岁
Bonnie was 15.
玛丽 16岁
Mary was 16.
特瑞丝17岁
And Therese was 17.
没人明白我们的数学老师
No one understood how Mrs. Lisbon and Mr. Lisbon,
里斯本先生和她夫人
our Math teacher,
怎么会造出这么美丽的尤物
had produced such beautiful creatures.
保罗·巴蒂诺说
Paul Baldino said
塞西利亚的初次自杀是他发现的
he found Cecilia on her first attempt.
是我发现她的
l was the one who found her.
我站在我家的下水道里
l was standing in the sewers around my house.
你能从那儿进入任何人的家
Through those tunnels you can get into anyone's house.
我们信以为真
when Paul said this We believed him
因为他爸是美国大兵 鲨鱼巴蒂诺
because Paul's dad was Sammy the Shark Baldino
我们知道他的逃生隧道经过下水道
and his escape tunnel led through the sewers.
我是想去
So l was thinking to see
看她们洗澡
one of those lesbian girls taking a shower.
对 是的
Yeah, right.
接着我进去了…到处都是血!
And l walk in... And l see blood everywhere!
所以我转身 顺着隧道原路返回
So l turned around and went right back out the tunnel.
我必须告诉你们这事 回见
l had to tell you guys that story. See you guys later.
我听说那是意外
l heard it was an accident.
不 根本不是意外 只怪她父母
lt was no accident. The parents are to blame.
我听说他们在马桶里找到刀片
l heard they found the razor in the toilet.
对塞西利亚自杀的原因 众说纷纭
Everyone had opinions why Cecilia tried to kill herself.
她不想死
That girl didn't want to die
只是想从家里逃出来
she just wanted out of that house.
她想摆脱那种装潢方式
She wanted out of that decorating scheme.
最流行的理论认为
The most popular theory
多米尼克·帕拉佐是罪魁祸首
held Dominic Palazzolo to blame.
多米尼克是个移民 暂时住在亲威家
Dominic was an immigrant who was staying with relatives
直到他的家人在新墨西哥安家
until his family got settled in New Mexico.
他是街坊里第一个戴墨镜的男孩
He was the first boy here to wear sunglasses.
来了还不到一周他就恋爱了
Within a week of arriving he'd fallen in love.
他心仪的对象不是塞西利亚
The object of his desire wasn't Cecilia,
而是黛安娜·波特
but Diana Porter.
我爱她!
l love her!
黛安娜去瑞士度假时 多米尼克逆天而行
When Diana Porter left on vacation, Dominic denounced God.
为表真心
And to prove to Olivia his love
他从亲戚家的房顶跳下去了
he jumped off the roof of his relatives' house.
我要给你看一些图象
l'm going to show you some images.
然后… 呃 你告诉我
And... er, you tell me
你想到了什么
what they remind you of.
好吗?
OK?
香蕉
A banana.
沼泽
A swamp.
爆炸头
An Afro.
我认为塞西利亚并不真想自杀
l don't think that Cecilia truly meant to end her life.
她的举动是求助的呐喊
Her act was a cry for help.
我知道你们非常严格
l know you're very strict,
但建立一些校外社交关系
but l think that Cecilia would benefit by having
对塞西利亚十分有益
a social outlet outside of the codification of school.
跟同龄的男孩交往交往
And interact with males her own age.
彼得帮里斯本先生
Peter helped Mr. Lisbon install a model
在教室建了个太阳系模型
of the solar system in his classroom.
作为回报 里斯本先生请他来吃晚饭
ln return, Mr. Lisbon invited him for dinner.
保佑我们 主啊为了这些
Bless us, O Lord, in these, Thy gifts
我们因耶稣之慷慨而收到的礼物 阿门
which we receive from Thy bounty through Christ. Amen.
阿门
Amen.
勒克斯 把上衣穿上 抱歉
Lux, please put your shirt on this instant. Sorry.
谢谢 宝贝儿 把盐递过来好吗?
Thank you, dear. Can you pass the salt, please?
要火腿吗? 谢谢
Ham? Thank you.
甜心 要点儿豌豆吗? 我讨厌豌豆
Sweetheart, would you like some peas? l hate peas.
火腿看上去真不错 亲爱的
lt's a nice looking ham, dear.
谢谢 亲爱的 真不错 妈妈
Well, thank you, honey. This is good, mum.
那么 彼得 你是个飞机狂热者吗?
So, Peter, are you an aviation enthusiast?
嗯 我不知道是否该把自己称作狂热者
Well, l don't know if l'd call myself an enthusiast.
我喜欢飞机
l like planes.
彼得 你是橄榄球队的吗?
Peter, are you on the football squad?
不 我玩儿这个 但不在队里
No. l play, but l'm not on the team.
哦 我知道了 不是队员
Oh, l see. Not a team player.
你喜欢摔跤吗?
Do you like to wrestle?
你还好吧?
Are you OK?
一种巴西青蛙今天被列入濒危物种了
A Brazilian frog entered the endangered species list today.
今年的第三种了
That's the third animal this year.
哦 宝贝儿 我头一次听说
Oh, dear. Darling, l've never heard of it.
不好意思 我可以用一下厕所吗? 当然
Excuse me. May l use the restroom? Of course.
楼下的坏了
The one down here isn't working very well.
去楼上塞西利亚的房间
Go upstairs through Cecilia's room.
好的 谢谢
OK, thanks.
卫生棉条
等等
Hold on.
我以为你死在里边了
l thought you'd died in there.
你霸占完厕所了吗? 我需要点东西
Are you done hogging the bathroom? l need something.
介意回避一下吗?
Do you mind?
非常谢谢 你忘了东西
Thank you. Are you forgetting something?
彼得 这是一片空气箔… 谢谢
Peter, here's an air foil... Thank you.
这是柏得利原理的应用
lt's a demonstration of Bernoulli's Principle.
举起…
Lift...
从那以后 里斯本家的就开始变样了
From then on the Lisbon house began to change.
几乎每天
Almost every day
甚至不用照看塞西利亚时
and even when she wasn't keeping an eye on Cecilia
勒克斯都会穿着游泳衣 坐在毛巾上晒黑
Lux would suntan on her towel, wearing a swimsuit
换来15分钟
that caused the knife sharpener
免费磨刀演示
to give her a 15 minute demonstration for free.
遵循医嘱
Following the doctor's orders
塞西利亚回家两周后
two weeks after Cecilia returned home
里斯本先生说服妻子允许女孩们举办了
Mr. Lisbon persuaded his wife to let the girls throw
短暂人生中第一场也是唯一一场派对
the first and the only party of their short lives.
好了 这样行吗?
There. ls that OK?
我得去换衣服了
l've got to get dressed.
欢迎 晚上好 里斯本太太
Welcome. Good evening, Mrs. Lisbon.
进来吧
Come on in.
派对在地下室
The party's in the basement.
左转 下楼梯
Just go to the left and then down the stairs.
嗨 我是邦妮
Hi, l'm Bonnie.
嗨… 我是蒂姆 很高兴见到你
Hi... Tim. Nice to meet you.
想要点潘趣酒吗? 好的
Would you like some punch? Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗨 谢谢
Hi. Thanks.
Hi. Thank you.
嘿 嗨
Hey. Hi.
想坐下吗? 好的
Do you want to sit down? Yeah.
你的智力测验分数怎么样?  还不错
How did your SATs go?  OK.
很好
Good.
你知道要申请哪所大学吗?
Do you know where you're applying yet?
没有 但我父母倾向于耶鲁
No, but my parents are pushing towards Yale.
因为那是我爸的母校 真不错
Because that's where my dad went. That's nice.
你要想象云层散开
You have to imagine the clouds opening up
亨驾驶着梅塞施米特(德国战斗机)冲出阳光
and out of the sun would come the Hun in his Messerschmitt.
孩子们 大你们两三岁的
And boys, just older than you
都开P51-B野马式战斗机
would be in this, the P51 B Mustang.
"B"代表舷窗
''B'' for bull's eye.
你听说过耶鲁吗? 是的
You've heard of Yale? Oh, yeah.
潘趣酒真不错 再来点?
This punch is fantastic. More?
里边有什么?
What's in it?
果汁 一些樱桃… 菠萝
Juices, some cherry... pineapple.
你知道 我… 我喜欢菠萝
You know, l... l love pineapple.
真的吗?
Really?
这宝贝出场了
This baby would come in.
就是它让英国打了胜仗
This won the war for the United Kingdom.
抱歉 没事
Excuse me. Sure.
就是这个仪器让模型运转
And it's this kind of equipment that makes a model work.
这是周
Here's Joe.
嗨 周 嗨
Hi, Joe. Hi.
如果他有需要 打电话叫我
lf he needs anything, call me.
他会没事的 I'm sure he'll be fine.
嗨 嗨
Hi. Hi.
周 很高兴见到你 你好吗?
Joe. Good to see you. How are you?
很高兴你今晚能来 你怎么样?
Glad you came tonight. How's it going?
你来的正好
You're just in time.
嗨
Hi.
看 如果你挠他下巴他耳朵就动
Look. His ears go if you scratch his chin.
周 唱你的歌
Joe, sing your song.
三宝颜的猴子没尾巴
菲律宾城市
Oh, the monkeys have no tails in Zamboanga
猴子没尾巴
Oh, the monkeys have no tails
被鲸鱼吃掉啦
They were bitten off by whales
三宝颜的猴子没尾巴
Oh, the monkeys have no tails in Zamboanga
真是首好歌 唱的好 周
Good song. Good job, Joe.
你从哪儿学的这首歌?
Where'd you learn that song?
我能离开一会儿吧?
Can l be excused?
只要你想 但宝贝儿 这是你的派对
lf you want to, my dear, but this is your party.
好吧 如果你想上楼就去吧 我们…
All right. lf you want to go upstairs, do. We'll just...
我们只能在没有你的情况下玩了
We'll just have to have fun without you.
看 他总是选正面
Look. He always chooses heads.
周 会是哪面? 正面
Joe, what's it going to be? Heads.
周 试试背面
Joe, try tails.
就是正面!
Heads it is!
再来 正面
Let's go. Heads.
正面! 再来一次
Heads! One more time.
在空中 周 正面
ln the air, Joe. Heads.
又是正面!
Heads it is!
再来一次 提前猜 周 正面
One more time. Call in the air, Joe. Heads.
正面 真不错
Heads. Not bad.
你怎么样?  很好
How are you doing?  Good.
他学的真快
He picked it up really well.
这是我最喜欢的歌
This is my favorite song.
你知道 你… 非常漂亮 像圣人一样
You know, you're... very beautiful. Like a saint.
有时间我可以给你画像
l could paint you some time.
谢谢
Thanks.
他们唱歌了吗?
Did they sing it?
哇 真好!
Wow, that's good!
天啊!
God!
哦 主啊!
Oh, Lord!
塞西利亚!
Cecilia!
哦 我的… 不 不 不!
Oh, my...! No! No, no, no!
不要看 转过去
Don't look. Turn around.
转过去! 亲爱的 转… 我的上帝!
Turn around! Darlings, turn... Oh, my God!
哦 耶稣!
Oh, Jesus!
求你了 上帝
Please, God.
我们到了
We're here now.
今天拒办葬礼
No funerals today.
他说她才13岁
He said she was only 13.
嗨 玛丽 你父母在家吗?
Hi, Mary. Are your parents home?
嗨 神父 请进
Hi, Father. Come in.
你好 神父
Oh. Hello, Father.
请坐
Please, sit down.
谢谢
Thanks.
拜托 那是界内球!
Come on, that was inside!
呃 不了 谢谢
Uh, no. No, thanks.
把夫人叫下来 聊一聊好吗?
How about we get the missus down here? Have a little chat?
恐怕她不舒服 I'm afraid she's under the weather.
她…
She's not...
谁也不见
seeing anybody.
嗯 她会见牧师的
Well, she'll see her priest.
这孩子每次都打不好界内球
This kid's a sucker for the inside ones every time.
每次都是
Every time.
抱歉
Excuse me.
神父…
Father...
双杀 神父
Double play, Father.
双杀
Double play.
里斯本太太?
Mrs. Lisbon?
我能进来吗? 好的
May l come in? OK.
你们好 女孩们 我想我们可以谈谈
Hello, girls. l thought we could talk.
你们想聊聊吗?
Do you feel like talking?
嗯… 如果你们想的话
Well... if you ever want to,
你们知道到哪儿找我
you know where to find me.
里斯本太太? 我是穆迪神父
Mrs. Lisbon? lt's Father Moody.
里斯本太太 你好
Mrs. Lisbon. Hello.
我想告诉你
l wanted you to know that
塞西利亚的死是个意外
l listed Cecilia's death as an accident.
一场必然发生的意外
An accident waiting to happen.
他们无法自欺欺人
They couldn't get a policy to cover it.
真是太危险了
I know.lt's incredibly dangerous.
我们试试
Let's give it a try.
准备好了? 123
Ready? One, two, three.
太悲伤了 真让我不敢相信
lt's so sad, l can't believe it happened.
你车里的锁链呢?
Have you got that chain in your truck?
开车!
Hit it!
我们收集的里斯本女孩的纪念品保存至今
Our collection of souvenirs of the Lisbon girls
从塞西利亚的日记开始
which still exists started with Cecilia's diary.
帕克从水管工那儿弄来的
Parkie had gotten it from the plumber's assistant
他在浴室的马桶边找到它
who'd found it in the bathroom.
蒂姆·微纳是智者 解密了它
Tim Weiner, the Brain, decoded it.
感情不稳定
Emotional instability.
看看"i"上的圆点 每个都如是
Look at the ''ls'', the dots on them. They're everywhere.
基本上 她是个梦想家
Basically, what we have here is a dreamer.
一个完全与现实脱节的人
Someone completely out of touch with reality.
她跳起来时 可能感觉自己要飞起来了
When she jumped, she probably thought she would fly.
2月13日 周一 今天我们吃的冰批萨
Monday, February 13th. Today we had frozen pizza.
周四 妈妈晚饭做了奶油玉米
Thursday. Mum made cream corn for dinner.
糟透了 看上去就像…
lt's the worst. lt looks like...
玛丽像白痴一样撞烂了门牙
Mary chipped a tooth acting like an idiot.
她大吵大闹 还不得不去补牙
She made a scene and had to get her tooth capped.
我猜看上去没两样 给我
lt looks normal. Give me that.
我就说她补过牙
l said she had a capped tooth.
榆树! 一棵要死的树能写多少页?
Elm trees! How many pages can you write about dying trees?
这是有关多米尼克的
Here's something about Dominic.
帕佐罗今天为了那阔绰婊子波特
Palazzolo jumped off the roof today
从屋顶上跳下来了
over that rich bitch, Porter.
你还能再蠢点么?
How stupid can you be?
今天我们乘船出海
Today we went out on the boat.
很冷 我们看到了几只鲸鱼
lt was cold. We saw a couple of whales.
勒克斯摸了鲸鱼 没想到它们这么臭
Lux stroked the whale. l didn't think they'd stink so much.
是它们肚子里的海草烂了
lt's the kelp in their bellies rotting.
我希望以后可以再去
l hope we can go again some time.
读读这个吧
Let's read that.
勒克斯看上了凯文…
Lux lusted over Kevin...
是"海兹"吗? 那个送垃圾的男人
ls it ''Heinz''? The garbage man.
勒克斯看上了凯文·海纳兹
Lux lusted over Kevin Haines,
那个送垃圾的男人
the garbage man.
她早上5点起床 在前门台阶上转悠
She'd wake up at 5am and hang out on the front steps.
就跟别人看不出来似的!
Like it wasn't completely obvious!
她把他的名字写在所有的内衣上
She wrote his name on all her underwear.
妈妈发现了 把所有凯文的字样都漂白了
Mum found them and bleached out all the Kevins.
勒克斯在床上哭了一整天
Lux is crying on her bed all day.
"这些树 像充满空气的肺叶"
''The trees, like lungs filling with air
"我姐姐 恶毒的那个 拉我的头发"
''My sister, the mean one, pulling my hair''
于是我们得以知晓她们的生活
And so we started to learn about their lives.
那些记忆汇集了我们未曾经历过的时光
Coming to hold the memories of times we hadn't experienced.
我们感受到作为女孩的被禁锢感
We felt the imprisonment of being a girl.
它是如何让你变得浮想联翩
How it made your mind active and dreamy.
让你了解到哪些颜色更搭
and how you knowing when colors went together
我们知道女孩们都有着缜密的内心
We knew that the girls were really women in disguise.
她们懂得爱情 甚至死亡
They understood love and even death.
我们能做的就是吸引她们
Our job was to create the noise that fascinated them.
她们对我们了如指掌
They knew everything about us
我们对她们却一无所知
but we couldn't fathom them at all.
嗨 里斯本太太 我是莉迪亚·皮尔 我在做… Hi. Mrs. Lisbon, I'm Lydia Perl. I'm putting together...
嗨 我是邦妮 这是玛丽 Oh! Hi, I'm Bonnie. This is Mary.
你好 女孩们 我来问你们几个问题… Hello, girls. I'm here to ask you a couple of questions...
是关于塞西利亚的
about Cecilia.
嗯? 好的 呃…
Yeah? Great. Um...
或许你们能告诉我一点她的事?
Maybe you could tell me a little bit about her?
她有没有什么特殊的兴趣爱好?
Did she have any special interests or hobbies?
她很喜欢写日记
She liked writing her journal a lot.
真棒
That is great.
好的 她有没…
OK. Did she...
她有说过要结束自己的生命吗?
Did she ever talk about ending her life?
出什么事了?
What's going on here?
你一定是里斯本太太
You must be Mrs. Lisbon.
我是莉迪亚·皮尔 我为二频道做一档节目 I'm Lydia Perl. I'm doing a piece for Channel Two.
这儿不欢迎你 皮尔小姐
You have to leave now, Miss Perl.
去年夏天 东部一位自杀少女
The suicide of a teenager last summer
引发了国民危机意识
has increased the awareness of a crisis.
我站在塞西利亚·里斯本家门前 一个13岁… I'm at the home where Cecilia Lisbon...
他们为什么不让她安息呢?
Why don't they let her rest in peace?
...爱好写诗 悲剧性的结束了自己的生命
..tragically put an end to her life.
心理学家一致认为 当代青少年
Psychologists agree that adolescence today
比起以前
is more fraught by pressures and complexities
更加复杂与脆弱
than in years past.
越来越多的医生说挫败感能引起暴力行为
Doctors say that frustration can lead to acts of violence
青少年无法将现实
whose reality the adolescent cannot separate
与虚幻区分开来
from its intended drama.
我烤了一个有老鼠药的馅饼
l baked a pie full of rat poison.
我觉得我可以悄悄吃下它
l thought l could eat it without it being suspicious.
我奶奶 她都86了…
My nana, who was 86...
她真的很喜欢甜食
She really likes sweets.
她吃了三块
She had three pieces.
我为这个母亲感到难过 I'm sorriest for the mother.
不 你一直想知道如何补救
You'd always wonder what you could have done.
我要挂了 再见
l got to go. See you later.
好的 再见
All right. Bye bye.
再见
Bye bye.
别担心
Don't worry.
他们把栅栏拆了
They took the fence out.
老天 你打鼾可够响的
God, you snore loud.
那些女孩有光明的前途
Those girls have a bright future ahead.
另一个却已成定局
The other one was just going to end up a cook.
直到9月7号
We didn't see the girls together as a group
我们才见到女孩们一块出现
until September 7th.
玛丽 勒克斯 邦妮和特瑞丝
Mary, Lux, Bonnie and Therese,
来到学校 就像什么也没发生过
came to school as though nothing had happened.
我们觉得只要仔细看
We felt if we looked hard
就会明白她们的感觉以及她们到底是谁
we'd understand their feelings and who they were.
好的 正如你记得的 这是维恩图
All right. These are Venn diagrams, as you remember.
我们有'A'和'B'相交
lf we have ''A'' and ''B'' intersecting.
这是'A'跟'B'
And ''A'' and ''B''.
如果'A'与'B'相交 就得出这块区域
lf ''A'' intersects ''B'', we have this area.
如果'A'与'B'相并
And if ''A'' is the union with ''B''
就得出整个圆和相交部分
we have all of the circle plus the intersection.
这就是交集和并集的规则
These are the laws of intersection and union. OK?
过的怎么样?
How's it going?
还不错
Not bad.
好的 "素描《淑女本色》...
OK. ''Do a character sketch on the following characters...
中的一个角色…"
from Portrait Of A Lady...''
第一个是… 罗夫
The first one is... Ralph.
呃… 他很好
Um... He was nice.
他死时我真的很难过
lt was really sad when he died.
哦 上帝 真不敢相信我刚才说了什么
Oh, my gosh. l can't believe l just said that.
我很抱歉
l am so sorry.
读到了惊人的自杀率
Reading about the alarming suicide rate,
我与伍德哈斯先生和其他几位老师谈过了
l talked to Mr. Woodhouse and some of the teachers here
意识到如此重大的问题
and realized that nothing about this serious matter
还未在学校里讨论过
has been discussed at this school.
随后就有绿色的小册子发下来
And quickly thereafter green pamphlets were distributed.
我们觉得绿色很欢快 也不算太欢快
We felt green was cheerful, but not too cheerful.
显然比红色要好
Certainly better than red.
册子里说
The pamphlets has told us
美国一天有80起自杀
there were 80 suicides a day in America
一年30,000起
30,000 a year.
茄子!
Cheese!
这敲响了我们
lt alerted us to danger signals
一直在找寻的危险警报
we couldn't help but look for.
里斯本的女孩子们瞳孔扩大了吗?
Were the Lisbon girls' pupils dilated?
她们对校园活动
Had they lost interest in school activities
体育运动或爱好失去兴趣了吗?
and sports and hobbies?
她们被同龄人孤立了吗?
Had they withdrawn from their peers?
嗨 我是瑞斯 Hi, I'm Chase.
我知道你是谁
l know who you are.
我这辈子就上过这一所学校
l've only been going to this school my whole life.
不用没话找话说
You don't have to talk to me.
比如说 我们有两种不同的经济类型
So, for example we have two different types of economics
第一种叫做宏观经济
the first one is called macroeconomics.
看
Look.
她在笑
She's laughing.
他让她笑了
He made her laugh.
这条狗嘴里哪吐得出象牙!
You never heard him say anything remotely intelligent!
与勒克斯交谈的男孩
The boys who talked with Lux
总是很蠢 也套不出任何信息
were always stupid and terrible sources of information.
..手风琴 她挺好
...squeezebox. She's all right.
告诉你吧 她绝对是学校里最辣的女孩
Let me tell you, she's the hottest girl in school.
想知道发生什么了?闻我的手指吧 伙计
You want to know what happened? Smell my fingers, man.
不 她不谈起塞西利亚
No, she didn't talk about Cecilia.
我们并没在说话 如果你知道我的意思
We weren't exactly talking, if you know what l mean.
认识勒克斯的唯一可靠的男孩
The only reliable boy who actually got to know Lux
是崔普·方汀
was Trip Fontaine.
他最近减掉了婴儿肥
Who had recently lost his baby fat
这很让女孩和妈妈们高兴
to the delight of girls and mothers alike.
我又迟到了
l'm late again.
哦 拜托!
Oh, come on!
谢谢
Thank you.
我们学校的所有女孩都爱上了崔普
All the girls at our school are in love with Trip.
所有的女孩 除了勒克斯
All the girls, except Lux.
崔普说 他是从上错第五节历史课
Trip said his passion for Lux was started
开始迷上勒克斯的
when he went into the wrong History class.
按照惯例 他在外边抽大麻
As was his custom, he went out to smoke the marijuana
他像糖尿病童打胰岛素一样按时吸食大麻
he took as regularly as a diabetic kid takes lnsulin.
那一天 他为了躲伍德哈斯先生
On this particular day, he avoided Mr. Woodhouse
溜进一间教室
by ducking into a class.
她是这个旋转世界中的静点
She was the still point of the turning world.
我从未忘记过她 从来没有
l never got over that girl. Never.
我爱过很多女人 但跟那不一样…
l've loved a lot of ladies, but not like that...
那是真的
That was real.
我永远忘不了第一次见她
l'll never forget the first time l saw her.
我不知道是什么打动了我 我不知道该怎么办
l didn't know what had hit me. l didn't know what to do.
因为与别的女孩总是得心应手
Because it was so easy with all the other girls
但她看都不看我
but she wouldn't look at me.
我…我不是主动追人的类型
l... l was never the kind to pursue.
如果你知道我的意思
lf you know what l mean.
她让我疯狂 伙计
That girl drove me crazy, man.
真好吃
Mmm, yummy.
勒克斯?
Lux?
嘿
Hey.
看看 只是面包片加肉而已
Look at it. lt's just meat on bread rolls.
谢谢 妈妈
Thanks, Mum.
崔普的爸爸帮不上什么忙
Trip's dad was little help.
嗯 首先 别给她打电话
Well, first off, don't call her on the phone.
这… 很奥妙
lt's all... lt's all subtlety.
有细微的差别
lt's all nuance.
是的 你只要在学校跟她说说话
Yeah. You just need to talk to her at school.
什么都行
About anything.
天气… 或作业
About the weather, or... school assignments.
只要找到
Anything to have the chance to
用眼神交流的机会
communicate with the language of eye contact.
还有对计划的信心
And project confidence.
别让头发挡着眼
And keep the hair out of your eyes.
感受那气氛
Feel the vibe.
做你自己就好了 对
Just do your stuff. Yeah.
"飓风"是自然界
The word ''hurricane'' was the name
最强的风暴
given to Nature's strongest storm.
当高压气团与低压气团相遇时
A hurricane occurs when high pressure and low pressure
就会形成飓风
masses of air come into contact with one another.
两种气团通常
There is often a significant difference
存在显著的气温差异
in temperature between the two masses.
一种是暖的 另一种是冷的
One mass is warm, while the other is cold.
暖气团上升 冷气团下降
The warmer air rises and the cooler air falls.
同时 低压气团
Likewise, the low pressure area
从高压气团的边缘滑下
slides down the sides of the high pressure area.
它们互相绕着彼此打转
They swirl around one another,
这就是风暴的开始
creating the beginnings of the storm.
从这幅
With this footage
美国海军气象巡逻机拍的图象来看
taken from US Navy weather patrol aircraft,
我们可以发现
we can observe two masses,
高低压气团
one high pressure and one low pressure
彼此接触了
coming in contact with one and another.
结果产生了极具破坏性
The result is a surging storm of tremendous strength
而且强有力的大风暴
that strikes with forceful determination.
尽管飓风
Even though the hurricane
是我们所知的最强风暴
is the most powerful storm known to us
它袭击大块陆地
it strikes large land areas
比如大洲或大的岛屿
such as continents or large islands.
而且消退缓慢
and slowly dies.
是蒙特顾马先生 他最恶心了
Mr. Montgomery, his ass is grass.
我想约你出去
l want to ask you out.
没门
Fat chance.
首先 我要去你家看电视 First, I'll go over to your house and watch the tube.
接着我会邀你出去 And then I'm gonna ask you out.
你真是人间尤物
You're the stone fox.
飓风
The hurricane.
大自然孕育出的
One of the most awesome and spectacular stories
最壮丽的史诗之一
Nature has to offer.
这是几频道? 五
What channel is this? Five.
哦 来看看…
Oh. Let's see...
"野生动物 穿越非洲卡拉哈里沙漠的旅行"
''Animals in The Wild. Journey through the African Kalahari
"观赏自然栖息地中的动物"
''and see animals in their natural habitat.''
我觉得听上去不错 你说呢?
l think that sounds nice, don't you?
广大的雨林最终让位给了草原
This huge rainforest eventually gives way to grasslands
它往四周无限延伸
that stretch to the horizon in all directions
这就是卡拉哈里
this is the Kalahari.
想再要点可乐吗? 是的 当然 谢谢
Do you want some more pop? Yeah, sure. Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
草原上的繁荣景象日渐衰竭
The wildlife spectacle played out on these grasslands,
而休眠中的雨林
and in recesses of the rainforest
将在世界各地苏醒
is unparalleled anywhere on Earth.
勒克斯 把脚放下去
Lux, put your feet down, honey.
卡拉哈里和浩瀚的苍穹
The Kalahari and its vast open sky
为兽群以及猎食的
provide a theatre for the life and death drama
大型猫科动物
played out by the herds
上演的生死循环戏码提供了舞台
and the great hunting cats that play on them.
哦 天哪!
Oh, my!
现在已经很晚了 亲爱的? let’s getting so late. Honey...?
我说已经很晚了
l said it's getting late.
好的 把电视关了吧
Oh. Well, let's hit the TV button.
是的 呃…
Right. Err...
好的 谢谢
OK. Thank you.
很高兴见到你 里斯本太太 是的
lt was nice to meet you Mrs. Lisbon. Yes.
晚安 再见
Good night. See you.
再见
Bye.
Goodbye.
我得回去
l've got to get back.
这是第四节课 你应该第五节课来 不是吗？
This is fourth period, l don't have you until fifth, do l?
我知道 我不是为数学来的 先生
l know. I'm not here for math today, sir.
我来告诉你
I'm here to tell you that my intentions for your daughter are entirely honorable.
我对你女儿的意图是真心的
什么意图?
What might those intentions be?
邀勒克斯去校园舞会
I want to ask Lux to the Homecoming Dance.
崔普 先坐下吧
Trip, why don't you sit down for a minute?
你知道 我妻子和我有明确的规则
You see, my wife and l have certain rules.
这约束了大女儿
They were the rules for the older girls.
我不能为了小女儿开先例
l can't change them for the younger ones.
就算我想 我妻子也不会同意的
Even if l wanted to, the wife wouldn't let me.
所以 如果你想再来看电视
So, if you want to come over and watch television again
那可以
that would be fine.
但你不能带勒克斯出去 特别是乘车
But you cannot take Lux out. Especially not in a car.
所以不好意思 年轻人 这是我们的规矩
So I'm sorry, son, that's just our policy.
好的 先生 如果我们几个男孩
OK, sir. What if a bunch of us guys
邀请你所有女儿们
and we took all your daughters out in a group
并在你规定的时间把她们送回去呢?
and had them back by the time you said?
你是橄榄球队的吗? 是的 先生
Are you on the football squad, son? Yes, sir.
什么位置? 四分卫
What position? Defence quarterback.
好样的
Ah, good.
我以前… 我当年可是中卫
l was a... l was a safety in my day.
嗯 那是个重要位置 先生
Well, that's a crucial position, sir.
得分全靠你了 不错!
Nothing between you and the goal line. Exactly!
哦 好吧 是这样的 先生
Oh, well. So the thing is, sir.
我们有场比赛
We've got the big game
之后还有舞会
and then afterwards we've got the dance.
其他人都有舞伴了
All the other guys are taking dates.
你很帅 很多女孩愿意跟你出去
You're good looking. Lots of girls would go with you.
我对她们不感兴趣 先生
I'm not interested in lots of girls, sir.
我会跟我妻子商量的 崔普 我尽量
I'll take it up with the wife, Trip. Do what l can.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
这可是门手艺
lt's a craft. Oh.
崔普·方汀和几个橄榄球队的男孩
Trip Fontaine and some of the boys in the football squad
想带她们去校园舞会
have asked to take the girls to the Homecoming Dance.
你知道我对那个怎么想
You know how l feel about that sort of thing.
我会保驾护航的 妈妈 拜托!
I'm a chaperone at the dance. Oh, please!
你爸爸和我等会儿再商量
Your father and l will discuss it later.
方汀先生 能跟你说句话吗?
Mr. Fontaine, may l speak with you, please?
关于你的请求 我和我妻子已经决定了…
My wife and l have come to a decision about your request...
好极了!
Yes!
我要带勒克斯·里斯本去校园舞会
I'm taking Lux Lisbon to Homecoming.
我还需要三个人带其他几个女孩
l need three guys to take the other girls.
我给你三支大麻 崔普
I'll give you three joints, Trip.
Pick me. We can take my dad's Caddy.
选我吧 我们可以开我爸的大众
你也得叫上我 崔普斯特
You gotta pick me, Tripster.
崔普 伙计 你欠我的
Trip, man. You owe me.
我那次从伍德哈斯手里救了你一命
l saved your ass with Woodhouse that time.
谢谢 爸爸 其他男孩是谁?
Thanks, Dad. Who are the other boys?
我们看看 帕克·德顿 杰克·克拉尼
Let's see. Parker Denton, Jake Conley
他是个好学生
he's a good student, dear
还有凯文·海德
and Kevin Head.
谁带谁? 各凭本事吧
Who's taking who? They're going to raffle us off.
女孩们选择哪件并不要紧
lt didn't make any difference which dress the girls chose.
里斯本太太在胸部加了一寸
Mrs. Lisbon added an inch to the bust line
腰部加了两寸
and two to the waist and hems.
裙子变成了四个一样的麻袋
The dresses became four identical sacks.
都准备好了? 是的
Everybody decent? Yeah.
好的 来吧
OK. Come on.
哦 抱歉 好了
Oh, I'm sorry. Here we go.
好的 离近点
Come on. Together.
说茄子
And cheddar cheese.
真兴奋!
Oh, it's so exciting!
准备好了吗?  好了 伙计
Are we ready?  Ready, man.
行动吧
Let's do it.
最后帕克因为那辆大众而胜出
ln the end Parkie won because of the Cadillac,
凯文·海德因为超猛的大麻
Kevin Head, because he had the killer weed,
还有周·黑尔·克拉尼 因为他获奖无数
and Joe Hill Conley because he won all the school prizes
崔普认为这些能打动里斯本夫妇
which Trip thought would impress Mr. and Mrs. Lisbon.
你们好 男孩们  你好 里斯本太太
Hello, boys.  Hello, Mrs. Lisbon.
进来吧  谢谢
Come in.  Thank you.
谁开车?  是我
Who's driving?  l am.
你有驾照多长时间了?
How long have you had your license?
两个月 但我学了一年
Two months. l was a learner for a year.
她们几乎没有乘车出去过
The girls almost never go out in cars.
最近有很多车祸
There's so many accidents now.
你们要小心  好的
I'm sure you'll be very careful.  Oh, yes, ma'am.
好的 最后评估完毕
OK. The third degree's over.
女孩们!
Girls!
我得走了 舞会见
I'd better go. See you at the dance.
到时见 里斯本先生
See you there, Mr. Lisbon.
再见 亲爱的
Bye, dear.
女孩们 下来
Girls. Come on down.
男孩们来了
The boys are here.
我们选的白色 因为不知道你们要穿什么
We got white ones. We didn't know what you were wearing
花店的人说白色百搭
and the flower guy said that white would go with anything.
很高兴你选白色
I'm glad you got white.
为什么不帮她们别上呢?
Why don't you pin them on?
崔普
好了 好了  我们走吧
There we go.  All right, let's do it.
太好了
Great.
再见 妈妈
Bye, Mum.
上帝 看啊! 那辆车又停在那儿了!
Oh, gosh, look! The car's there again!
我确定李先生跟她有一腿
I'm sure Mr. Lea's having an affair with her.
我见过他跟着她进了洗衣室
I saw her followed her into the laundry room.
他那个红鼻子真可悲
He's so sad with that red nose.
可能是个酒鬼
Probably an alcoholic.
海兹家的人呢？你知道他们是纳粹
Yep,what about the Hessed?The Hesses are Nazis.
是纳粹的拥护者
They're Nazi sympathizers.
他们在史沃兹小姐
They had a fit when Miss Schwartz
进网球俱乐部时大发雷霆
tried to join the tennis club.
铝边侧线不错!他们真觉得这样没问题吗?
Nice aluminum siding! Do they really think that looks OK?
彼特丝先生从电视上订的
Mr. Peters ordered that from TV later that night.
那是巴蒂诺家的烧烤木桩
lt's a Baldinos barbecue tree stump.
我从没见过他们在那上面烧烤!
l have never seen a barbecue on that thing!
事实上 那是鲨鱼老兵的逃生隧道
Actually, it's an escape tunnel for the Shark.
通向河边和他的快艇
lt leads to the river and his speedboat.
保罗经常去
Paul goes down there all the time.
他可以从下水道去任何一家的地下室
He can get into anyone's basement through the sewers.
不可能! 是的
No way! Yeah.
爸爸会闻出来的 不会 我有薄荷糖
Dad'll smell it on you. No, l got mints.
他会闻到你衣服上的味
He'll smell it on your clothes.
我就说有人在厕所里抽烟
I'll say they were smoking in the toilets.
死前先破个雏吧(烟圈) 真恶心
Don't let it die a virgin. That's gross.
成熟点吧 克拉尼
Yeah, grow up, Conley.
想跳舞吗? 当然
Do you want to dance? Sure.
跳舞吗?
Dance?
天气真不错 是吧?
We've been having such lovely weather, don't you think?
是的 不错… 很好
Yeah, we have... Nice.
晚上好 能请大家注意一下吗?
Good evening. Could l have your attention for a moment?
我希望大家能过的愉快 看起来正是如此
l hope you're having a good time. lt sure looks like it.
舞会委员会可是使出浑身解数
The dance committee really outdid themselves this time.
返校节舞王舞后的投票开始
I'd like to open the voting for Homecoming King and Queen.
投票箱就在那边 请投票
The ballot box is over there, so please vote.
随后我们将宣布结果
And we'll make the announcement in a little while.
谢谢
Thank you.
有人看到你过来吗? 没有
Did anybody see you come in? No.
你呢? 没有
What about you? No.
你会喜欢的
You'll love it.
蜜桃松子酒
Peach schnapps.
漂亮女孩都喜欢
Babes love it.
味道真好
That stuff tastes really good.
我不想要 谢谢
l don't want any, thanks.
拜托 就尝一下 尝一小口
Go on, just a taste. A tiny taste.
别当乖乖女了
Don't be such a goody goody.
别咽下去
Don't swallow it.
大家请注意
Can l have everyone's attention?
请大家鼓掌欢迎
I'd like you to put your hands together
今年的舞王舞后…
for this year's Kind and Queen...
崔普·方汀和勒克斯·里斯本
Trip Fontaine and Lux Lisbon.
这是我最快乐的时光!
I'm having the best time!
我们出去走走吧
Let's go for a walk.
还是算了 我一会儿得回来
I'd better not. l've got to go back in a minute.
我们可以盯着车
We can keep an eye on the car.
他们不会不等我们就走的
They won't leave without us.
我爸爸…
My dad...
告诉他你要把皇冠放到柜子里
Tell him you're putting the crown in your locker.
看到那块草皮了吗? 嗯?
See that divot there? Uh huh?
我今天就在那儿放倒了那小子
That's where l reamed this guy today.
全防住了  真的吗?
A cross body block.  Really?
可能他们跟你爸爸回去了吧?  未必
Maybe they went home with your dad?  l doubt it.
我们完了 是勒克斯 不是我们
We're cooked. Luxy is, we're not.
谁有薄荷糖?
Does anyone have any mints?
抱歉 没有
Sorry. No.
再见 帕克
Bye, Parkie.
我们送你们到门口  不 不必了
We'll walk you to the door.  No, don't.
为什么不行?  真的不必了
Why not?  Just don't.
好的
OK.
你会给我打电话吗?
Will you call me?
当然!
Absolutely!
再见
Bye.
再见 再见
Bye. Bye.
你还好吗? 你去哪儿了?
Are you OK? Where have you been?
看看你这个样子! 进屋去!
Look at the state of you! Get in the house!
那晚我独自走回家了
l walked home alone that night.
不关心她怎么回去 很奇怪
l didn't care how she got home. lt was weird.
我是说 我喜欢她 我非常喜欢她
l mean, l liked her. l liked her a lot.
但那晚在操场…
But out there on the field...
那就是另一回事了
lt was just different then.
那是我最后一次见她
That was the last time l saw her.
你知道 大多数人从没尝过那种爱情
You know, most people will never taste that kind of love.
但至少我经历过一次 对吗?
But at least l tasted it once, right?
您应该去开六点钟的群会了
lt's time for your six o'clock group meeting.
对勒克斯的晚归
Given Lux's failure to make curfew
大家都预料到了坏结果
everyone expected a crackdown.
但没人想到会如此惨烈
But few anticipated it would be so drastic.
女孩们被禁止上学
The girls were taken out of school
里斯本太太
and Mrs. Lisbon shut the house
以最大的安全措施封锁了她家
in maximum security isolation.
她不止不让女孩们上学
She did more than taking the girls out of school.
那个星期天 在一场教堂说教后
That Sunday, after a spirited church sermon.
里斯本太太让勒克斯销毁她的唱片
Mrs. Lisbon made Lux destroy her records.
快点!
Now!
但是 妈妈…
But, Mum...
我最后再说一遍 勒克斯
This is final, Luxy.
这不公平  我说快点
That's not fair.  l said now.
就现在 勒克斯!
Now, Luxy!
快点儿
Come on.
热吻乐队 请别让我这么做
Kiss. Please don't make me do this.
烧了它
Burn it.
妈妈 空中铁匠!
Oh, Mum, Aerosmith!
拜托 别让我这么做
Come on, please don't make me burn this.
拜托…
Please...
什么味道?
What's that smell?
好吧 先至此为止
All right, that'll do for now.
给我 给我
Give me these... Give me these.
我扔到垃圾箱里
I'll put them in the trash.
从此我们开始看见勒克斯
This was around the time we began seeing Lux
在屋顶跟不同男人做爱
making love on the roof with random men.
她脱光了吗?  看不出来
ls she naked?  You can't tell.
对准
Get it focused.
别吵了 等轮到你再说
Will you stop? Wait your turn.
他们在干什么?
What are they doing?
他们在滚来滚去
They're rolling around up there.
等等 她在他上面
Hold on. She's on him.
他的手插在她头发里
He's rubbing his hands through her hair.
让我看看  不 这是我的望远镜 瑞斯
Let me look.  No. No, it's my telescope, Chase.
好的 还有什么?
Yes and what else?
那男人穿着汉堡屋的制服
That man's in a burger chalet uniform.
给我看看
Let me see.
是啊谁知道下一个有艳遇的是谁
Yeah. You never think that those guys ever get lucky.
接着她问我 刚才的事算不算下流
Then she asks me if what we'd just done was dirty.
我知道该怎么说 我说不是
l knew what to say. l said no.
接着她拉着我的手问"你喜欢我 是吗?"
Then she goes, ''You like me, don't you?''
我什么也没说 最好让小妞们猜测
l didn't say anything. lt's best to keep chicks guessing.
瑞斯 宝贝儿 晚饭前得练习小提琴
Chase, honey. Come practice your violin before dinner.
你不会相信的
You're not going to believe it.
勒克斯今晚又上屋顶了!
Lux is on the roof again tonight!
她的手在下滑 我得看看
Her hands are moving down. l gotta see this.
太美了  现在是她在上面了
This is beautiful.  Now she's on top of him.
她在做什么 伙计?  等等
What's she doing, man?  Wait.
现在做完了 他起来了
Now they're done. He's getting up.
就这样? 真是快
That's it? That was quick.
...再加1 如果指数是时间
...plus one. And if the exponential is time
那我们就有…
then you'd have as you approach...
早安
Oh, good morning.
用光合作用做早餐了吗?
Have we photosynthesized our breakfast today?
你好 罗纳德 嗨 哈里
Hello, Ronald. Hi, Harry.
你的女儿们已经两周没来上学了
Your daughters haven't been at school for over two weeks.
你查过了?
Have you checked out back?
他们找了个新数学老师
They've found a new Math teacher.
他得找新工作了 我知道
He'll have to get another job. l know.
女孩们还要这样被关多久?
How long can those girls be cooped up like that?
走开 这是我们的树
Go away. This is our tree.
女孩们 女孩们…为时已晚 这棵树已经死了
Girls, girls... lt's a little late. This tree is dead.
为什么不让它自生自灭呢?
Why don't you leave it up to Nature?
那样所有树都会死
lf we did, there'd be no trees left.
反正最后结果也一样
That's what it's going to be like anyway.
如果真菌没从欧洲扩散
lf they didn't bring the fungus from Europe
就不会这样了
this wouldn't have happened.
好的 走吧
OK. Let's go.
不走?
No?
这样 我收到命令要砍掉你们的榆树
That's it. l have an order to cut down your elm tree,
但你的孩子们不让
but your kids won't let us.
你怎么知道树有病
How do you know it's sick.
相信我 它叶子都黄了
Believe me or not, it has yellow leaves,
真的死了 it’s dead for Christsake.
Are you familiar with arbotect?
知道毒疗法吗
Our daughter show us an article
我女儿给我看的文章
says it was less aggressive therapy.
里说这创伤较小
lt doesn't work.
没用
l leave that tree there, they'll all go.
要是把它留着 明年所有树都会死
早晚都会死嘛
They could anyway.
听着 我不想打电话给警察
Look, l don't want to call the police.
我女儿站在自家草坪上
Our daughters are standing on our lawn.
这犯哪门子的罪?
Since when is that a crime?
克里弗 看到那些穿睡衣的女孩了吗?
Clive. See those girls in their nighties?
就拍那儿 That's what I want. That’s the shot that l want.
亲爱的 再往前一点
Honey, you'll have to move forward.
我想拍穿睡衣的女孩
l want those girls in their nighties.
后面一点 放松点
Let's back up. Give me some more slack.
好了 这样行吗? 好
There you go.ls that good? Great.
去年引起国内一片哗然的
Four sisters of Cecilia Lisbon,
东部自杀少女塞西利亚·里斯本
the teenager whose suicide last summer
她的四个姐姐关注全国性的问题
focused awareness on a national problem,
不顾危险
put their own lives in jeopardy
想保护塞西利亚深爱的榆树
by trying to protect the elm that Cecilia so dearly loved.
一阴天你的黑眼圈就很明显
The circles under your eyes come out when it's overcast
你得涂…
so you need to wear...
接下来的几个星期 我们基本见不到她们
For the next few weeks we hardly saw the girls at all.
乔依并没照约定给特瑞丝打电话
Joe didn't call Therese as he had promised.
勒克斯再也没跟崔普说过话
And Lux never spoke to Trip again.
你真是人间尤物
You're the stone fox.
女孩们与世界的唯一联系
The girls' only contact with the outside world
是她们订的杂志
was through the catalogues they ordered.
她们的邮箱里
I started filled Lisbon's mailbox with
充满了时尚图片
pictures of high end fashions
还有异国旅游手册
and brochures for exotic vacations.
因为不能外出
Unable to go anywhere
她们乘着想像游览暹罗神庙
they traveled in their imaginations to Siamese temples,
又或经过
or past an old man with a leaf broom
打扫满地青苔的日本老人
tidying a moss carpeted speck of Japan.
我们订了同样的杂志
We ordered the same catalogues
与她们在蒙尘的小道上远足
and hiked through dusty passes with the girls.
时不时停下
Stopping every now and then
帮她们整理背包
to help them with their backpacks.
将手放在她们温暖 湿润的肩膀上
Placing our hands on their warm, moist shoulders,
共赏日落的余辉
and gazing off at the fire sunsets.
我们和她们一起在凉亭喝茶
We drank tea with them in a water pavilion.
我们随心所欲
We did whatever we wanted.
塞西利亚没有死 她是加尔各答的新娘
Cecilia hadn't died. She was a bride in Calcutta.
无法实现的旅行
The only way we felt close to the girls
是我们走近她们的唯一方法
was through these impossible excursions
那让我们铭记终生
which have scared us forever,
这些梦比真实的女人更让我们快乐
making us happier with dreams than wives.
我们收集她们所有的东西
Collecting everything we could of theirs,
女孩们萦绕在我们脑海里
the Lisbon girls wouldn't leave our minds,
但她们在消逝
but they were slipping away.
她们眼睛的颜色渐渐淡去
The colors of their eyes faded along
连同消失的酒窝
with the exact location of their dimples.
五个变成了四个
From five they had become four,
如行尸走肉般活着…
and they were all living in the dead...
变成了影子
becoming shadows.
如果她们没有联系我们
We were losing them
我们就彻底失去她们了
when the girls contacted us.
1长 2短
One long. Two short.
1长 记下了?
One long. Have you got that?
就这样 好的
That's it. OK.
救助
Help.
送来
Send.
Bo... Bo.
Bo... Bo Bo... Bo.
Bobo? Bobo 就是这个… Bobo
Bobo? Bobo. That's it... Bobo.
"救助 送来Bobo" 我还以为你懂摩尔斯密码!
''Help. Send Bobo.'' l thought you knew Morse code!
有东西给你
There's something here for you.
记得我们吗? 你会帮忙吗? 给瑞斯
我也收到一张
l got one, too.
亲爱的无论是谁 告诉催普我不爱他了 他是个混蛋
我们绞尽脑汁地想联系她们
We racked our brains for a way of contacting them.
汤姆建议我们往她们家放风筝
Tom suggested we fly a kite
上面绑上纸条
with a message alongside the house.
但这有逻辑上的错误
But that had logistical problems.
最后 答案很简单
ln the end, the answer was simple to come up with
我们给她们打电话
we called them on the telephone.
准备
Get ready.
你好? 行动!
Hello? Go!
嗨 是我
Hello, it's me
我为你我的关系苦恼了很久
I've thought about us for a long, long time
打给我们 7270487
Call us. 7270487.
该死 是她们
Shit. lt's them.
回首昨日
To think that only yesterday
我曾无忧无虑
I was cheerful, bright and gay
对无人知晓的未来
Looking forward to who wouldn't do
和一切充满希翼
The role I was about to play?
危难之际
In my hour of need
我是真的 再次孤身一人 本就如此
I truly am indeed Alone again naturally
投入我怀抱 当你孤单的时候
Run to me whenever you're lonely
投入我怀抱 每当你需要依靠
Run to me if you need a shoulder
某些时刻 你的他应该成熟而可靠
Now and then, you need someone older
那么 宝贝 来到我的怀抱
so darling, you run to me
遥远的彼岸
So far away
是否仍有人原地驻足
Doesn't anybody stay in one place anymore
看到你出现在门前 很幸福
It would be so fine to see your face at my door
却无从得知 你将时光虚度
Doesn't help to know You're just time away
我要回家了 明天见  回见
I'm going home. See you tomorrow.  See you later.
我们快窒息了 勒克斯  你在这儿很安全
We're suffocating.  Lux, you're safe here.
我没法呼吸
l can't breathe.
没人接
No answer.
明天午夜 等我们的信号
几点了?  到时候了
What time is it?  Any time now.
伙计们 就在那儿  是吗?
Guys, there it is.  What?
是的 是她们
Yeah, it's them.
我们走
Let's go.
我有我妈的车钥匙
l've got the keys to my mum's car.
也许我们该敲敲门
Maybe we should knock.
我们到了
We're here.
到点了 我们在等你们呢
lt's about time. We've been waiting for you guys.
我们有车 装满了油 想去哪儿都行
We've got a car. We'll take you anywhere you want to go.
是辆美洲豹 车厢很大
lt's a Cougar. lt's got a big trunk.
我能坐前排吗? 当然
Can l sit up front? Sure.
谁挨着我坐?
Which one of you is going to sit next to me?
你父母在哪儿?  睡觉
Where are your parents?  Asleep.
你姐妹们呢? 马上就来
What about your sisters? They're coming.
快点 很晚了
Come on. lt's getting late.
再等5分钟
Wait five minutes.
得等我父母都睡着
We have to wait until my parents are asleep.
得再等会儿 我妈失眠
They take forever. My mum's an insomniac.
最好开我们的车 空间大些
We'd better take our car, there's more room.
你开得了旅行车吗?
Think you can handle a station wagon?
当然 又不是手动档 是吧?
Sure. lt's not a stick, is it?
是的 没问题
No. Yeah, no problem.
我能驾驶吗?  当然
Will you let me steer?  Sure.
我们得走了 我听到有动静 可以是你妈妈
We should go. l just heard something. lt could be your mum.
进来吧
Come on in.
我去车里等
I'll go wait in the car.
你们在这儿等她们吧
You guys wait here for my sisters.
只要摸到一个 就能让我疯狂!
These girls make me crazy. lf l just felt one of them once!
怎么了?
What?
我们永远无法弄清发生的顺序
We would never be sure about the sequence of events.
到现在我们还在讨论
We argue about it still.
很可能 邦妮死时
Most likely, Bonnie had died
我们正在客厅里
while we were waiting in the living room
幻想着高速公路
dreaming of highways.
随后玛丽把头伸进了烤箱里
Mary put her head in the oven shortly thereafter.
特瑞丝吃了很多安眠药
Therese, stuffed with sleeping pills,
在我们到之前就走了
was gone by the time we got there.
勒克斯是最后一个
Lux was the last to go.
现在是周日下午四点钟
lt's four o'clock on Sunday afternoon.
你知道你的孩子在哪儿吗?
Do you know where your children are?
邦妮 是里斯本姐妹中最小的一个…
Bonnie, the younger Lisbon sister...
特瑞丝·里斯本 她很爱马 曾经写信…
Therese Lisbon, a horse lover, has written to...
玛丽想当啦啦队长
Mary wanted to be a cheerleader,
但她妈妈不同意
but her mother wouldn't let her.
在她们的家中自杀…
..suicide in their house...
我愤怒到无以复加
l wasn't able to express the anger l felt.
...莉迪亚·皮尔 八频道新闻
...Lydia Perl, Channel Eight News.
我的女儿们并不缺少爱
None of my daughters lacked for any love.
我们家里有足够的爱
There was plenty of love in our house.
我就是弄不懂为什么
l never understood why.
自杀事件后
After the suicides,
里斯本夫妇放弃了
Mr and Mrs Lisbon gave up
过正常生活的愿望
any attempt to lead a normal life.
他们让海德力先生收拾了房子
They had Mr. Hadley pack up the house,
把能卖的家具都贱卖了
and sell the furniture in a garage sale.
里斯本先生把房子卖给一对波士顿年轻夫妇
Mr. Lisbon sold the house to a young couple from Boston.
当然
We, of course,
我们从垃圾堆里拣来了家庭相册
took the family photos that were put out with the trash.
最终 我们拼凑出了谜团的答案
ln the end, we had pieces of the puzzle,
但裂痕仍在
but how to put them together,gaps still remained.
形状奇怪的空白
Oddly shaped emptiness,
在环绕之物的映射下
mapped by what surrounded them,
就像叫不出名字的国度
like countries we couldn't name.
徘徊在她们身后的并非生命
What lingered after them was not life,
而是现实生活中最琐碎的物件
but the most trivial list of mundane facts
墙上滴答作响的钟摆
a clock ticking on the wall,
正午昏暗的房间
a room dim at noon,
人类自私的暴行
the outrageousness of a human being
自行其道
thinking only of herself
我们开始徒劳的试图忘记她们
We began the impossible process of trying to forget them.
我们的父母做能的更好
Our parents were able to do this,
他们回到网球组和鸡尾酒会上
returning to their tennis foursomes and cocktails
处变不惊
as though they'd seen it all before.
盛夏又到来了
lt was full fledged summer again
在塞西利亚割腕一年后
over a year after Cecilia had slit her wrists
空气中充满了毒药
spreading the poison in the air.
疯长的植物增加了湖里的磷肥
A spill at the plant increased the lake's phosphates
并产生大量藻类
and produced algae
沼泽的气味
so that the swamp's smell
环绕着这座气派的公馆
filled the air infiltrating the genteel mansions.
少女们初登社会
Debutantes cried at coming out in a season
每个人却只记得那时的恶臭
remembered for its bad smell.
而奥康纳家人的别出心裁
The O'Connors ingeniously made
给女儿爱丽丝的
the theme of their daughter
成人派对命名为"窒息"
Alice's debutante party ''Asphyxiation''.
像大家一样
Like everyone else,
我们渐渐忘了里斯本家的女孩
we went to forget about the Lisbon girls.
她会让他心脏病发的
She'll give him a heart attack.
嗨 帕克
Hi, Parkie.
会装死的虫子如何?
How about the acting bug?
我从檎基抓来的
l caught it from Kinky.
我今晚想宣布
And l want to announce tonight that
下个秋天 爱丽丝就要去纽瀚文上学了
next fall Alice is going to school in Newhaven.
我听说那里的语法学校十分了得
l hear they have a great grammar school up there.
事实上 就是萨姆的爸爸建的 是吧?
ln fact, Sam's father built it, didn't he?
是医院 保罗
The hospital, Paul.
我们十分为爱丽丝自豪 万分自豪
We're so proud of Alice. We couldn't be prouder.
这杯敬她
Here's to her.
我受够了 再见 残酷世界
l've had it. Goodbye cruel world.
不 不 不! 你不会理解我的
No, no, no! You don't understand me.
我是少年 我有烦恼
I'm a teenager, l got problems.
这些年来 有许多关于她们的流言蜚语
So much has been said about the girls over the years,
但我们从未找到过答案
but we have never found an answer.
这与她们的早逝无关
lt didn't matter how old they had been,
抑或因为她们是女孩
or that they were girls,
只因为我们爱过她们
but only that we had loved them.
她们始终听不见
And that they hadn't heard us call them,
我们在门外的呐喊
still do not hear us calling them out of those rooms
她们始终在那里孤独着
where they went to be alone for all time.
我们永远无法将它们拼贴完整
We will never find the pieces to put them back together.